Nashica Walters

Timmins, Ontario
Email: nashicawalters@gmail.com || Phone: 780.933.0864

 $Linked In: www.linked in.com/in/nashica-walters/ \parallel Git Hub: github.com/nashwalters$

Portfolio: nashwalters.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

Full- Stack Web Developer with extensive customer service and project management experience. Proven problem solving/ analytical skills, known for working well under pressure, strong attention to detail and a passion for life-long learning.

Technical Skills

Visual Studio Code, HTML, CSS, Git, Github, Bootstrap, Bulma, ES6, JavaScript, jQuery, Moment.js, APIs, JSON, AJAX, Node.js

Projects

Vibe Cannon

Group Project

HTML, CSS, Bulma, jQuery, API's, Github Pages

Vibe Cannon is an entertainment application that allows the user to access their favorite songs. In addition, the user is able to get information about the song that they can also share, watch music videos as well as access lyrics if they are available.

- Github Repo: https://github.com/CodyYuill/Vibe-Cannon
- Deployed Project: https://codyyuill.github.io/Vibe-Cannon/

Weather Dashboard

HTML, CSS, Bulma, ¡Query, API's, Github Pages

The weather dashboard allows the user to see the weather outlook for multiple cities so you can plan a trip accordingly.

- Github Repo: https://github.com/nashwalters/weather-dash
- Deployed Project: https://nashwalters.github.io/weather-dash/

Work Day Scheduler

HTML, CSS, jQuery, Moment.js

This is a simple calendar/scheduler application that allows users to save events for each hour of the work day.

- Github Repo: https://github.com/nashwalters/day-scheduler
- Deployed Project: https://nashwalters.github.io/day-scheduler/

Professional Experience

District Operations Coordinator

October 2018 – present

H & R Block Canada

- Recruit, interview, hire and onboard office level associates.
- Coordinate the set up and shut down of all offices in the district.
- Maintain the asset management inventory and process invoice payments.
- Handle client complaints and ensure that associates are focused on providing professional and personalized service to clients.
- Serve as a brand ambassador by promoting the H & R Block brand as well as participate in executing the sales plan to grow market share as well as retain the current client base.

Assistant Operations Manager- Rooms

June 2018 – October 2018

Delta by Marriott Edmonton South

- Oversees daily shift operations of the front office and the housekeeping department and ensures compliance with all policies, standards, and procedures.
- Use budgets, operating statements and payroll progress reports as needed to assist in the management of the Room Operations.
- Participates in the management of departmental controllable expenses to achieve or exceed budgeted goals.
- Implementing targets, KPI's, policies and procedures to ensure brand standards are maintained

Front Office Manager

September 2017– June 2018

Best Western Hotel Grande Prairie

- Best Western certified sales champion, working along with the regional sales manager on prospecting potential clients and rate negotiations.
- Provide guidance and motivation to team members on basic yield management and selling principles to maximize RevPAR and achieve/ exceed room budgets.
- Responsible for overseeing accounts receivables and collections.
- Oversee the operations functions of the front desk, as well as all hotel departments in absence of the general manager.
- Health and safety auditor and committee member.

Front Office Manager

April 2013 – September 2017

Sandman Hotel, Grande Prairie

- Prepare daily transaction summary and closing balance reports.
- Bank reconciliation.
- Month ending reporting which includes: petty cash summary, DABS and inventory.
- Responsible for accounts receivables and GL coding for accounts payable.
- Health and safety auditor.

Education

Full-Stack Web Development Course

2021

Carleton University

BSc. Hospitality and Tourism Management

2010

University of Technology, Jamaica and The University of the West Indies, Mona